[
  {
    "question": "The perspective of Henry David Thoreau’s writings can best be described as",
    "a": "forward-looking",
    "b": "realistic",
    "c": "solitary",
    "d": "optimistic",
    "e": "unaffected",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Alma Thomas’s ethnicity is best described as",
    "a": "Asian-American",
    "b": "European-American",
    "c": "African-American",
    "d": "Mexican-American",
    "e": "Native American",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "From which of the following colleges did Alma Thomas graduate?",
    "a": "American University",
    "b": "Howard University",
    "c": "Georgetown University",
    "d": "Boston University",
    "e": "Harvard",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "The acronym NASA stand for",
    "a": "National Air and Space Administration",
    "b": "National Aeronautic Shuttle Administration",
    "c": "National Aeronautics and Space Administration",
    "d": "National Aerospace Study Administration",
    "e": "National Aerospace Science Administration",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of flower was included in Alma Thomas’s “Earth Paintings” series?",
    "a": "chrysanthemum",
    "b": "tulip",
    "c": "cherry blossom",
    "d": "peony",
    "e": "dandelion",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are Alma Thomas’s paintings not considered true eco art?",
    "a": "They focused too much on human subjects.",
    "b": "Their ethical orientation was not fully formed.",
    "c": "Art critics were prejudiced against her.",
    "d": "They made heavy use of abstraction.",
    "e": "They were too small in scale.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Alma Thomas borrowed the name “Snoopy” for her painting Snoopy– Early Sun Display on Earth from",
    "a": "a satellite",
    "b": "a lunar landing module",
    "c": "an astronaut’s nickname",
    "d": "the first dog in space",
    "e": "a cartoon dog",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Approximately how wide are the brushstrokes in Snoopy– Early Sun Display on Earth?",
    "a": "1.5 inches",
    "b": "1 inch",
    "c": "0.5 inches",
    "d": "2 inches",
    "e": "2.5 inches",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What perspective technique does Alma Thomas use in Snoopy– Early Sun Display on Earth?",
    "a": "aerial perspective",
    "b": "traditional linear perspective",
    "c": "ambiguous depth",
    "d": "sfumato",
    "e": "close zoom",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which city did Lady Bird Johnson seek to beautify through increased natural spaces?",
    "a": "Boston",
    "b": "New York City",
    "c": "Washington D.C.",
    "d": "Baltimore",
    "e": "Richmond",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Redwood National park was created by the same president as",
    "a": "Acadia National Park",
    "b": "Yellowstone National Park",
    "c": "Grand Canyon National Park",
    "d": "North Cascades National Park",
    "e": "Arches National Park",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which president passed the Wilderness Act?",
    "a": "Ronald Reagan",
    "b": "John F. Kennedy",
    "c": "Richard Nixon",
    "d": "Lyndon B. Johnson",
    "e": "Jimmy Carter",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which environmentalist published the Whole Earth Catalog?",
    "a": "James Lovelock",
    "b": "Nathan Hare",
    "c": "Arne Nass",
    "d": "Lady Bird Johnson",
    "e": "Stewart Brand",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did Nathan Hare write “Black Ecology”?",
    "a": "1992",
    "b": "1964",
    "c": "1958",
    "d": "1970",
    "e": "1980",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "The movement which seeks to combat the racial effects of ecological threats is known as",
    "a": "ecological racialism",
    "b": "environmental justice",
    "c": "abatement inclusion",
    "d": "pollution equity",
    "e": "green-space activism",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which government operation was responsible for evacuating Mendieta and her siblings?",
    "a": "Operation Mongoose",
    "b": "Operation New Life",
    "c": "Operation Pedro Pan",
    "d": "Operation Allies Refuge",
    "e": "Operation Frequent Wind",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Mendieta’s sister’s name?",
    "a": "Ramona",
    "b": "Renée",
    "c": "Raquelín",
    "d": "Raphaela",
    "e": "Rana",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which state did Mendieta live in after leaving her homeland?",
    "a": "Iowa",
    "b": "Illinois",
    "c": "Oklahoma",
    "d": "Texas",
    "e": "Indiana",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did Mendieta draw on both North American and Cuban aesthetics for her multimedia works?",
    "a": "to remember the people she met on her journey",
    "b": "to pay homage to both of her homes",
    "c": "to explain her complex background to an unaware audience",
    "d": "to bridge the painful divide in her cultures",
    "e": "to display the underlying similarities between the cultures",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which two concepts did Mendieta explore when she first shifted her focus to performance art?",
    "a": "war and health",
    "b": "family and history",
    "c": "art and culture",
    "d": "gender and identity",
    "e": "sexuality and education",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work foreshadowed Mendieta’s “Silueta” series?",
    "a": "Chicken Piece",
    "b": "Flowers on Body",
    "c": "Grass on Woman",
    "d": "Features on Woman",
    "e": "Double Negative",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which year did Mendieta create Feathers on Woman?",
    "a": "1978",
    "b": "1971",
    "c": "1972",
    "d": "1980",
    "e": "1972",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which influence did Mendieta NOT use for Chicken Piece?",
    "a": "Columbian cultural sites",
    "b": "Viennese Actionists",
    "c": "Chris Burden",
    "d": "Cuban SanterÍa rituals",
    "e": "Carolee Schneemann",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Mexican city prompted Mendieta to rediscover her connection to her hometown?",
    "a": "Mexico City",
    "b": "Leon",
    "c": "Tijuana",
    "d": "Oaxaca",
    "e": "Puebla",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which setting did Mendieta use for Flowers on Body?",
    "a": "a cathedral",
    "b": "a battlefield",
    "c": "a museum",
    "d": "an archaeological site",
    "e": "a graveyard",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which concept is LEAST present in “Siluetas?”",
    "a": "permanence",
    "b": "nature",
    "c": "culture",
    "d": "femininity",
    "e": "home",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which influence did Mendieta say was the strongest for “Siluetas?”",
    "a": "visiting Mexico",
    "b": "leaving her homeland",
    "c": "reuniting with family",
    "d": "Afro-Caribbean practices",
    "e": "other Earthwork artists",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Mendieta criticized other Earthwork artists for their",
    "a": "greedy intent",
    "b": "shallow ideas",
    "c": "uneducated audience",
    "d": "disruptive art",
    "e": "simple displays",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which power did Mendieta refer to as “magic?”",
    "a": "honesty",
    "b": "fertility",
    "c": "spirituality",
    "d": "femininity",
    "e": "creativity",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which concept did Mendieta NOT explore in her works?",
    "a": "violence",
    "b": "culture",
    "c": "wealth",
    "d": "death",
    "e": "performance",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  }
]